<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Foure paradoxes 1 A byshop and a minister is all one. 2 A byshoppe or deacon shoulde not bee called Grace, Lord, or exercise such authoritie. 3 A popish priest is no lawful minister of the gospel. 4 Canon chauncellours, &amp; officials are no meete officers in the churche of God.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1570</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 26 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 13 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A08908</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 19185</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S101477</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99837291</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99837291</idno>
            <idno type="VID">1606</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A08908)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 1606)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 998:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Foure paradoxes 1 A byshop and a minister is all one. 2 A byshoppe or deacon shoulde not bee called Grace, Lord, or exercise such authoritie. 3 A popish priest is no lawful minister of the gospel. 4 Canon chauncellours, &amp; officials are no meete officers in the churche of God.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[26] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>In Paules Churchyarde, at the signe of the Lucrece, by Thomas Purfoote,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[ca. 1570]]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: pi¹ A-C⁴.</note>
                  <note>Publication date from STC.</note>
                  <note>Imprint and printer's device (McKerrow 151) on verso of pi1, bound before A1, title page.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Sarah Wingo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Sarah Wingo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="frontispiece">
            <pb facs="tcp:1606:1"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <head>LVCRECIA-ROMANA</head>
                  <figDesc>woodcut, Lucrece holding a dager to her chest</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </p>
            <p>¶ <hi>Imprinted at London in</hi> Paules Churchyarde, at the ſigne of the <hi>Lucrece,</hi> by <hi>Thomas Purfoote.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="table_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:1606:1"/>
            <head>¶ FOVRE PARA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>DOXES.</head>
            <list>
               <item>1 A Byſhop and a Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter is all one.</item>
               <item>2 A Byſhoppe or Deacon ſhoulde not bee called Grace, Lord, or exerciſe ſuch authoritie.</item>
               <item>3 A popiſh Prieſt is no law ful Miniſter of the goſpel</item>
               <item>4 Canon Chauncellours, &amp; Officials are no meete Officers in the Churche of God.</item>
            </list>
            <q>
               <p>
                  <bibl>Actes. 14.</bibl>
               </p>
               <p>Quae doctrina noua haec?</p>
               <p>What new doctrine is this?</p>
            </q>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:1606:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:1606:2"/>
            <div n="1" type="paradox">
               <head>1 A Byſhop and a Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter is all one.</head>
               <p>Let a man ſo thinke of vs, as of<note place="margin">1. Cori. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 2. Cor. 10<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </note> the <hi>Miniſters</hi> of Chriſt, and <hi>Diſpoſers</hi> of the ſecretes of God.</p>
               <p>A <hi>Byſhop</hi> muſt be vnreproueable,<note place="margin">1. Timo. 3<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Titus. 1.</note> apte to teache. &amp;c. Lykewyſe muſt <hi>Deacons.</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Paule and Timothee the <hi>Seruantes</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Philip. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Coloſ. 1.</note> of Ieſus Chriſt, to all the Saintes in Chriſt Ieſus, which are at Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lippi, with the <hi>Byſhops</hi> &amp; <hi>Deacons.</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The <hi>Elders</hi> which among you, I<note place="margin">1. Petee. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </note> beſeche, which alſo am an <hi>Elder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Whereof I am made a <hi>Miniſter,</hi> by<note place="margin">Ephe. 3.</note> the gyft of the grace of God geuen vnto me. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Take heede therefore vnto your<note place="margin">Actes. 20<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </note> ſelues, and to all the flocke, wherof the holy Ghoſt hath made you Ouer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeers. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Wee are Gods <hi>Labourers,</hi> ye are<note place="margin">1. Cori. 3<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </note> Gods huſbandry.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:3"/>
               <p>Who alſo hath made vs able Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters.<note place="margin">2. Cori. 3.</note> &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Thus in the place of the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters of the law, as <hi>Prieſtes</hi> &amp; <hi>Leuites,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Lamb. in ſuis para doxis.</note> there be onely two kynde<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> of <hi>Miniſters</hi> vnder the Goſpell, <hi>Byſhops</hi> &amp; <hi>Deacons:</hi> and the <hi>Byſhops</hi> haue ſundry names as <hi>Miniſters, Diſpoſers, Seruants, Elders, Ouerſears, Labourers, Prophets, Euangeliſts, Preachers, Apoſtels,</hi> and yet all are one.</p>
               <p>Betwene a <hi>Byſhop</hi> and a <hi>Miniſter,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Chryſ. in Timoth. cap. 5.</note> there is almoſt <hi>no difference:</hi> for the charge of the Church is committed to the <hi>Miniſter,</hi> &amp; the thynges which are ſpoken of the <hi>Byſhop,</hi> do apper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tayne to the <hi>Miniſter.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The <hi>Miniſter</hi> differeth not fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the<note place="margin">Aerius.</note> 
                  <hi>Byſhop,</hi> the order is <hi>all one.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>None of vs appointeth him ſelfe<note place="margin">Augu. de bap. lib. 3 cap. 3. Cypri. in Concil. Carthag. Ambr. in Timo. 1. cap. 3.</note> to be a <hi>Byſhop</hi> of <hi>Byſhops,</hi> nether dri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ueth hys <hi>Felowes</hi> into a <hi>neceſſitie</hi> of o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bedience.</p>
               <p>The ordering of a <hi>Byſhop</hi> and of a <hi>Miniſter</hi> is one, for they be both the <hi>Diſpoſers</hi> of Gods ſecretes.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:3"/>
               <p>A <hi>Prieſt</hi> and a <hi>Byſhop</hi> are but <hi>one</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Hiero. in Epiſt. ad Tit. ca. 1.</note> 
                  <hi>thyng,</hi> and before that by the infla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming of the Deuyl, partes were ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken in religion. &amp;c. The Churches wer gouerned by the <hi>common conſent</hi> of the <hi>Prieſtes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Apoſtel teacheth playnelyt,<note place="margin">Idem ad Euagr.</note> that the <hi>Byſhops</hi> &amp; <hi>Miniſters</hi> are <hi>all one.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The things ſpoken of the <hi>Biſhops,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Theoph in Titu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>.</note> do belong vnto the <hi>Miniſters,</hi> neither is the one <hi>aboue</hi> the other.</p>
               <p>A <hi>Byſhop</hi> rather by cuſtome, then<note place="margin">Panor. cap. 4. de conſuet.</note> by Gods lawe, is aboue the <hi>Miniſter:</hi> yea, in times paſt one <hi>Miniſter</hi> did or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dayne an <hi>other.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Hierome ſeemeth to matche all<note place="margin">Eraſ. in ſchol. in Epiſt. ad Euagriu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                  </note> 
                  <hi>Byſhops</hi> together, as if they were all equally the Apoſtels ſucceſſors: and he thinketh not anye <hi>Byſhop</hi> to bee <hi>leſſe</hi> then an other, for that hee is <hi>poorer:</hi> nor <hi>greater</hi> then an other, for that he is <hi>rycher.</hi> &amp;c. And further he thincketh that a <hi>Byſhop</hi> is no <hi>better</hi> then any <hi>Prieſt.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Muſcul. in locis co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mu.</note>
               </p>
               <p>There is but One onely hie Prieſt
<pb facs="tcp:1606:4"/> in the new Teſtament.</p>
               <p>Antichriſt had hys begynnyng,<note place="margin">Bullyng ſerm. 58. in Apo.</note> when the cuſtome began, that <hi>By<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhops</hi> ſhoulde bee preferred before Prieſtes.<note place="margin">Caluin. lib. 4. In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitu. Pet Mar in lib. Iu.</note>
               </p>
               <p>The Paſtors haue all <hi>one charge</hi> with the Apoſtels.</p>
               <p>For Biſhops to haue <hi>large Dioceſſes</hi> is a <hi>filthy</hi> diſeaſe.</p>
               <p>When the Church began to haue<note place="margin">Beza in cap. 1. ad Philip.</note> one <hi>chiefe,</hi> as a <hi>Preſident,</hi> or Ouerſear of the people, then the Deuyll <hi>began</hi> to practiſe his peruer<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>itie, and to lay the <hi>foundation</hi> of his tyranny.</p>
               <p>There is <hi>no difference</hi> betwene a<note place="margin">Herm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>. Bod<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s. Hamel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tonus VVeſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mether. Spangel bergius.</note> 
                  <hi>Byſhop</hi> and a <hi>Miniſter.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Byſhops</hi> and <hi>Prieſtes</hi> are <hi>equall.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>All <hi>Byſhops</hi> are <hi>Miniſters,</hi> and the reſt are <hi>Deacons.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>A <hi>Paſtor</hi> of the Church is a perſon which is called lawfully, by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thoritie and commaundement of God, vnto the cure of ſoules to <hi>teache</hi> the doctrine of the Goſpell, and to <hi>miniſter</hi> the Sacramentes.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:4"/>
               <p>Is it ſo horrible an hereſy to ſay,<note place="margin">Iewel co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tra Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding. R. T. in ſuo opu: in quo di lucide ap<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>paret Pe<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>trum no<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> fuiſſe Romae. Radul: Gualter. Tigurin in Acta: apoſtol. cap. 1.</note> that by the ſcriptures of God a <hi>By<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop</hi> and a <hi>Prieſt</hi> is <hi>all one?</hi>
               </p>
               <p>An <hi>Elder</hi> and a <hi>Byſhop</hi> were bothe one at the beginning, <hi>Act. 20. ver. 17. 18.</hi> which two verſes conferred, wyll ſhew the ſame.</p>
               <p>Therefore they often tymes ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledge, and confeſſe an <hi>equalitie</hi> and condition among the Apoſtels. For if that Matthias receaued a part of that Miniſterie, which was as well committed to Peter, as o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers: then none of them obtayned the <hi>whole,</hi> whereby he myght be cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led the <hi>Head,</hi> or <hi>Lord</hi> of others, nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther could Peters authority in prea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ching the Goſpell be <hi>greater</hi> then ey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Iohns or Matthias, becauſe they all receaued but <hi>one,</hi> and the <hi>ſame</hi> commaundement of the Lord Ieſus, as is playne.</p>
               <p>The ſeuen ſtarres are the <hi>Meſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Apoc. 1, Bvlling. ſerm. 6.</note> of the ſeuen Congtegations.</p>
               <p>Starres bee called Angels, An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gels
<pb facs="tcp:1606:5"/> be Gods <hi>Meſſengers, &amp; Paſtors</hi> of Churches, ſo called in the ſecond &amp; third chapter of Malachie.</p>
               <p>The ſeuen ſtarres in ſignification<note place="margin">Bale.</note> are the <hi>Meſſengers</hi> of Gods woord, or the <hi>Apoſtolique Preachers,</hi> appoynted to the ſeuen Congregatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s in Alia, and in them, to <hi>all the world.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Chriſt gaue the <hi>lyke</hi> authority vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to<note place="margin">Cypr. de ſimplic. prelato<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum.</note> euery one of the Apoſtels.</p>
               <p>This is the mynde of the Engliſh church at Geneua, in their Annota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions before the Chapters, and vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the new Teſtament: This is the conſent of the Church of Scotland: this the opinion of all the reformed Churches in Europe. And thys is mynde of S. Paule in the .xx. of the Actes, and of Hierome and Theo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dorete vpon the ſame place.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Obiec∣tion. </seg>
                  </label> Marke the Euangeliſt was By<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop of Alexandria.</p>
               <p>Iames and Symon Cananeus were Biſhops of Hieruſalem.</p>
               <p>Peter was Biſhop of Antioche.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:5"/>
               <p>Ignatius ſucceeded Peter in that Biſhopricke.</p>
               <p>Policarpus was biſhop of Smyr<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na, and ſo of others.</p>
               <p>Epiphanius alſo wryteth in the defence of a Biſhoplike diſtinction, and authoritie, &amp; therefore to haue Biſhops is a thyng allowed by the autority of the primitiue Church.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Anſwer. </seg>
                  </label> That there ſhould be Biſhops is a thing graunted, but y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> they ſhould be aboue the Miniſters, as that is plainly denied, ſo cannot the co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry be lightly proued: For ſ. Marke was none otherwyſe Biſhop at A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lexandria, then S. Thomas prea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ching to the Meedes, Parthians, and Perſians.</p>
               <p>Saynt Iames and Simon Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naneus were but as Simon Zelo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tes preachyng in Mauritania and Aphricke.</p>
               <p>Peter was in no ampler ſort By<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop of Antioche, the Iudas Thad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deus preaching in Meſopotamia.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:6"/>
               <p>Ignacius was at Antioche, as Oneſimus at Epheſus.</p>
               <p>Polycarpus was at Smyrna, but as Simon was at Boſtrum.</p>
               <p>As for Epiphanius, <hi>fuit Epiſcopus, &amp; voluit arroga<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ter ſuam tueri dignitatem,</hi> he was a Biſhop, and he would <hi>arro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gantly</hi> maintaine and vpholde hys <hi>dignitie.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Queſtiō. </seg>
                  </label> Hereunto we may adde a <hi>queſtion,</hi> whether it hath bene, or maye bee profitable to the Churche of God, that one <hi>Miniſter</hi> ſhould be ſet <hi>on hygh</hi> and <hi>aboue</hi> the reſt.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Anſwer. </seg>
                  </label> Firſt touching <hi>Rome,</hi> this politi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal ſuperiority hath ſet him on horſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>backe, and a gog on all hys pryde, whereby the Church of God was, and is afflicted, Chriſtian Princes iniured, religion vtterly ſubuerted, and ſuperſtition mainly defended.</p>
               <p>Then concerning Englande, thys preheminence in Prieſtes was the cauſe why William Rufus, &amp; Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry the firſt were troubled by Anſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mus,
<pb facs="tcp:1606:6"/> Henry the ſecond moleſted by Thomas Becket, Kyng Iohn by Steuen Langthon, Henry the third by Edmunde, Edward the firſt, by Iohn Peckham, and Robert Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chelſey, kyng Richard with Willia<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> Biſhop of Ely, &amp; ſo of other kinges, who euery one in his time had ſom what to do with <hi>Byſhops Archbishops</hi> and <hi>Cardinals:</hi> ſo that the end of this ſuperiority is the <hi>diſhonouriug</hi> of God, the <hi>troubling</hi> of Princes, the <hi>heaping</hi> together of great wealth, <hi>abuſing</hi> of the goodes of the Church, and <hi>mole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſting</hi> &amp; <hi>wringing</hi> of all chriſtian people.</p>
               <p>Thus wee ſee it manifeſtly pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued, if ſelfe wyl and ambition <hi>raygne</hi> not, that no primacie eyther in the <hi>Pope,</hi> or in any other <hi>Prieſt,</hi> maye bee mayntained: And we haue it pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued by the holy Ghoſt in S. Paule, and in S. Peter. Chryſoſtome con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cludeth ſo, Aerius affirmeth it, Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guſtine aloweth it, Cypria<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> ſo ſaith, Ambroſe agreeth thereunto, Theo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>philact
<pb facs="tcp:1606:7"/> confeſſeth it, Hierom auou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheth it, Panormitan ſo writeth, E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raſinus ſo thinketh, it is the mynde of Theodorete, of Muſculus, of Bul<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>linger, of Peter Martir, of Caluin, of Beza, of Gualter, &amp; of other the godly and learned, wherfore to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clude, we may wel reaſon thus:</p>
               <p>All things <hi>diſagreing</hi> from the god<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and learned-mens iudgement, &amp; from the holy Ghoſt his teachyng, are to be <hi>reiected:</hi> Therfore that one <hi>Miniſter</hi> ſhoulde be <hi>aboue</hi> his fellowe brethren, is to be <hi>reiected.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Adde hereunto the <hi>Minor,</hi> &amp; then the argument holdeth in <hi>Darij.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Seyng that the degree of a By<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop,<note place="margin">Melanet: in opuſc: de vtra<expan>
                        <am>
                           <g ref="char:abque"/>
                        </am>
                        <ex>que</ex>
                     </expan> parte Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cramenti &amp;c.</note> and of a Paſtor doo not differ by the law of God, it is euident that if any Paſtor or Curate make anye godly ordinaunce in his Church, it is confirmed by the law of God.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="paradox">
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:7"/>
               <head>2 A Byſhoppe or Deacon ſhoulde not bee called Grace, Lord, Honour, or exerciſe ſuch authoritie.</head>
               <p>Ye know that the <hi>Lordes</hi> of the Ge<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tiles<note place="margin">Math. 20</note> haue <hi>dominion</hi> ouer them, and they that are <hi>great</hi> exerciſe <hi>authoritie</hi> ouer them, but it ſhal not be ſo <hi>among you.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They that beare <hi>rule</hi> ouer them,<note place="margin">Luke. 22</note> are called <hi>gratious Lordes,</hi> but ye ſhall <hi>not</hi> be ſo.</p>
               <p>Feede the flocke of God, which de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pendeth<note place="margin">1. Pete. 5.</note> vpon you. &amp;c. not as though ye were <hi>Lordes</hi> ouer Gods heritage.</p>
               <p>Wee preache not our ſelues, but<note place="margin">2. Cor. 4.</note> Chriſt Ieſus the Lorde, and our ſelues your <hi>Seruantes</hi> for Ieſus fake.</p>
               <p>He that is called to a Biſhoprick,<note place="margin">Orig: in Eſaiam homil: 7 Hieron: ad Nepo tianum.</note> is not called to a <hi>Soueraigntie,</hi> but vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the <hi>ſeruice</hi> of the whole Church.</p>
               <p>Let Biſhops vnderſta<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>d that they
<pb facs="tcp:1606:8"/> are Miniſters, and not <hi>Lordes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>He that truly <hi>ſucceedeth</hi> Paule, wil<note place="margin">Bern. ad Eugeniu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                  </note> ſay with hym, not as though wee were <hi>Lordes</hi> ouer your fayth, but hel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers of your ioy.</p>
               <p>We ought not to bee lyfted vp on<note place="margin">Chryſo: ſermo: Gregor: Nazian: ad Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>copium. Barnes in ſua ſupplic.</note> 
                  <hi>high,</hi> and to ſeeme <hi>mightie.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The luſt of ſtrife and deſire and of <hi>Lordſhip</hi> raygne there.</p>
               <p>They ſhal know openly by mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſt ſcriptures our fained hipocriſy, and that we ought not to be <hi>Lordes</hi> of the Parlame<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t, nor to haue any place of worldly <hi>honour</hi> amo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>g the people.</p>
               <p>Here was an enſample howe they<note place="margin">Eraſ. in Mark. 12</note> ought to knowe <hi>nothing</hi> of Prynces <hi>affaires,</hi> whoſe dutye it is to <hi>preache</hi> &amp; <hi>teache</hi> heanenly matters.</p>
               <p>The king keeping his Parlame<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t,<note place="margin">Te<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>pore Edouar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>di primi.</note> with hys Barons, the <hi>Archbiſhops</hi> and <hi>Byſhops</hi> being ſhut forth, it was enacted.</p>
               <p>The Biſhop of Rome ought to be<note place="margin">Epiſco: Aragen:</note> the <hi>Miniſter</hi> of the Church.</p>
               <p>If Chriſt the ſonne of God, came<note place="margin">Segoni- us in co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                     <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil: Baſil</note>
                  <pb facs="tcp:1606:8"/> not to be miniſtred vnto, but to mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter &amp; ſerue, how then can hys Vicar haue any <hi>dominion,</hi> or be called Lord, as you Panormitan will affirme?</p>
               <p>They do euyl that ſeeke to be By<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhops,<note place="margin">Muſc: i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> locis co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                     <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mun.</note> to the intent they would be notable <hi>aboue</hi> the reſt.</p>
               <p>The Biſhop was not ſo <hi>aboue</hi> the<note place="margin">Caluin. lib. 4. ca. 4. ſer. 2. Gardin: de vera obedie<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t.</note> reſt in <hi>honor</hi> and <hi>dignitie,</hi> that he had a <hi>dominion</hi> ouer his <hi>fellowes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dominions</hi> and hygh <hi>authorities</hi> bee as it were ſtops and impedimentes to the attaining of eternal felicitie, and they are to bee caſt awaye and contemned. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Byſhops</hi> maye not bee <hi>Princes,</hi> and<note place="margin">Franciſc. La<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>bert.</note> 
                  <hi>Lordes</hi> of any place, but of their own houſholde: for it is <hi>contrary</hi> to bee a <hi>Byſhop</hi> and <hi>Prince,</hi> for to be a <hi>Byſhop,</hi> is to be a <hi>Miniſter</hi> &amp; faithfull <hi>Seruant.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">An: Gil: ſuper Michea<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>.</note>
               </p>
               <p>But becauſe they did loue y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> 
                  <hi>worldly kingdome,</hi> and <hi>lordſhip,</hi> more then the kingdome of heaue<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, as Chriſt here chargeth them, that they wyll bee great, and be called <hi>Lordes.</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:9"/>
               <p>Wher it is a Miniſterie that is here<note place="margin">Gualter: Tiguri: in Acta Apoſt.</note> entreated of, it is fooliſhnes, and great abſurditie vnder colour ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to ſeeke <hi>reuerence</hi> of the people, or to exerciſe tira<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>nical <hi>lordſhip</hi> ouer the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               </p>
               <p>Therefore the <hi>Popes kyngdome</hi> is of<note place="margin">Guiliel. Tyndal.</note> this world: For here one ſorte are your <hi>Grace,</hi> your <hi>Holynes,</hi> your <hi>Father<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood:</hi> an other my <hi>Lord</hi> Byſhop, my <hi>Lord</hi> Abbot, my <hi>Lord</hi> Prior: an other Maiſter <hi>Doctor,</hi> Father <hi>Bacheler,</hi> ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter <hi>Parſon,</hi> Maiſter <hi>Vicar,</hi> and at the laſt co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>meth in ſimple <hi>Sir Iohn,</hi> &amp; eueri one <hi>raygneth</hi> ouer other with might, and haue euery <hi>Ruler</hi> his <hi>Pryſon,</hi> his <hi>Iayler,</hi> his <hi>chaynes,</hi> his <hi>tormentes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Thou wilt ſay: thou canſt not ſee<note place="margin">Tyndal.</note> how ther ſhould be any good order in that kingdome, wher none were better then other, and wher the Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periour had not a law to <hi>compel</hi> the inferiour with violence.</p>
               <p>It belongeth onely vnto the <hi>Prince</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Barnes.</note> to haue ful power ouer all worldlye courſes: for the <hi>Biſhops</hi> may not v<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurpe
<pb facs="tcp:1606:9"/> any power that belongeth vn to the <hi>ſworde:</hi> ſo that S. Paule ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keth<note place="margin">Roma. 13. Orig: in Roma. cap. 13.</note> all men from their <hi>ſubiection,</hi> &amp; Origene taketh awaye all crimes from their <hi>correction.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Here it appeareth euidentlye by the <hi>Law</hi> of God, by the <hi>example</hi> of our ſauiour Chriſt, by the holy <hi>wry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinges</hi> of the Apoſtels, and by the <hi>ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition</hi> of the auncient fathers, and others, that neither the Byſhop of Rome, nor anye other Byſhop or Deacon, ought to haue &amp; take the name of <hi>gracious Lordes,</hi> nor yet that they ſhould exerciſe any ſuch <hi>autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritie,</hi> and therefore wee maye hence reaſon thus:</p>
               <p>Al <hi>Succeſſours</hi> of the Apoſtels ought<note place="margin">Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ra. Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ri.</note> to <hi>ſhunne</hi> the titles of <hi>gracious Lords.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>All our <hi>Byſhops</hi> are <hi>Succeſſours</hi> of the Apoſtels.</p>
               <p>Therefore al our <hi>Byſhops</hi> ought to <hi>Thunne</hi> the titles of <hi>gracious Lordes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Againe: Nothyng <hi>diſagreing</hi> from the ſcriptures is to be <hi>allowed:</hi>
               </p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:10"/>
               <p>But that a <hi>Miniſter</hi> would bee cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led <hi>Grace</hi> or Lord, is <hi>diſagreing</hi> from the ſcriptures:</p>
               <p>Therefore it is not to be allowed.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="paradox">
               <head>3 A popiſh Prieſt is no law ful Miniſter of the goſpel</head>
               <p>A <hi>Byſhop</hi> muſt bee <hi>vnreprouable.</hi> &amp;c.<note place="margin">1. Tim. 3.</note> 
                  <hi>apte</hi> to teache. &amp;c. but a papal Prieſt is no ſuch man.</p>
               <p>The <hi>Miniſters</hi> muſt bee choſen by<note place="margin">Actss. 14. Titus. 1.</note> the <hi>Faithfull,</hi> with praiers &amp; faſtyng, and in the aſſembly of the faithfull: but the <hi>popiſh Prieſt</hi> is choſen by an <hi>Idolater,</hi> without true praiers, or fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſting, and in the companye of irreli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gious Papiſtes: therefore he is no <hi>true Miniſter.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>He which is <hi>lawfully</hi> ordayned, &amp;<note place="margin">Cypr: lib Epiſt. 4.</note> holdeth the Apoſtolicall &amp; Euange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licall tradition, is a <hi>Miniſter:</hi> but ſuch a one is not the poipiſh Prieſt: the proofe is playne.</p>
               <p>The Sinagoge of the Pope is
<pb facs="tcp:1606:10"/> more aduerſarie to Chriſt, then the<note place="margin">Franciſe Lamber ad prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cip: lan ſan:</note> Turke: therfore his Prieſtes are no <hi>lawfull Miniſters</hi> of the Goſpell.</p>
               <p>Conſider the <hi>definition</hi> of a Paſtor, and it muſt needes euidentlye ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare, that a popiſh Prieſt is no <hi>law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full Miniſter.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Queſtion </seg>
                  </label> If a popiſh Prieſt <hi>refuſe</hi> his papa<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cie, &amp; being co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>uerted vnto the Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pell, may he not be a <hi>Miniſter,</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any further calling, and ſo <hi>admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter</hi> the Sacramentes?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Anſwer </seg>
                  </label> No: for it was not <hi>lawfull</hi> in the primitiue Church, for the <hi>Conuertes,</hi> without further calling to bee Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters of the Sacramentes.</p>
               <p>And if a meere <hi>Lay man</hi> is no law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full Miniſter, no more is the papal Prieſt.</p>
               <p>Againe, if a turkiſh Prieſt beyng <hi>conuerted,</hi> may not yet adminiſter the Lordes Supper, nor without fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>calling</hi> Baptize anye, no more may the papiſticall Prieſt.</p>
               <p>It is hereſie to affirme, that the
<pb facs="tcp:1606:11"/> Pope, Cardinals, Biſhops, wythall<note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>amber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>us in pa <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ad:</note> his kyngdome, bee of the <hi>Church</hi> of God, which is meke, al pure &amp; holy.</p>
               <p>Wherefore, conſidering the <hi>premi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes,</hi> weighing the <hi>practiſe</hi> of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtels, and looking to the order of the primitiue Church, we maye reaſon thus, for it is effectuall:</p>
               <p>None being ordayned by the ſy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagog<note place="margin">Ce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent.</note> of <hi>Antichriſt,</hi> is a lawfull Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter:</p>
               <p>All popiſh Prieſtes are ordayned by the ſynagog of <hi>Antichriſt:</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Therefore no popiſhe Prieſt is a lawfull <hi>Miniſter.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="paradox">
               <head>4 No Canon Chauncel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, or popiſh Officiall, is a meete Officer in the Church of God.</head>
               <p>They are <hi>ignorant</hi> in the woord of God, <hi>ſkylfull</hi> in the Popes law one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lye, geuen not to reforme thynges
<pb facs="tcp:1606:11"/> rightlye, but to <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ake</hi> and <hi>reape</hi> theyr own commodity: they are friendes to the Pope, they are <hi>foes</hi> to all good Proteſtantes, and ſhoulde ſuche haue any gouernment in a <hi>reformed</hi> Church?</p>
               <p>If it was thought good at Baſil, when reformation began, to dyſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>place <hi>.xii. popiſh Senatours,</hi> ſhall it bee neceſſarie for vs to retayne popiſhe Chauncellours, and papal <hi>Proctors?</hi>
               </p>
               <p>For <hi>Canoniſtes</hi> to haue authority to excommunicate, abſolue, ſuſpende, and interdicte, what is it but to em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brace the Popes kingdome ſtyll?</p>
               <p>The <hi>Canon</hi> lawe is full of <hi>hereſies,</hi> and ſhall the profeſſors thereof bee Iudges in Chriſtes Church?</p>
               <p>Examine the ſtate of the Church, by the ſpace of a <hi>thouſand yeares,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſaid lawes wer preſcribed, and you ſhall finde that the congre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gation of God did ſafelye runne ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardes heauen, vnder the ſweete yoke of our Lord.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:1606:12"/>
               <p>The <hi>Officials</hi> of Archbiſhops, for<note place="margin">Queri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> hanc ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buere princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pes Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man: in Concil. Noren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berg: an: 1523.</note> the moſt part are <hi>vnlearned</hi> and <hi>vnable</hi> men, beſides that, men of yuell con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s, taking thought for nothing but onely for <hi>money,</hi> &amp;c. beſydes this the Laitie are miſerably <hi>ſpoyled</hi> and <hi>robbed</hi> of their goods by theſe <hi>lyght,</hi> and <hi>vyle Officials.</hi> In whoſe conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence there is no ſparke of Chriſtian pity and godlynes, but onely a wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked deſire, and couetouſnes. Which thyng the Archbiſhops &amp; Biſhops, if they were in deede ſuche as they are <hi>called,</hi> that is to ſay, <hi>Paſtors,</hi> and <hi>Shepheards</hi> of Chriſt, without doubt, they would no longer ſuffer, or co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit Chriſtes flocke to ſuch <hi>wycked</hi> &amp; <hi>offenſiue</hi> Paſtors, to be fed and nou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhed.</p>
               <p>What? ſhal we accompt of thoſe, in whoſe <hi>Court</hi> S. Paule is no doc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor?<note place="margin">Pſalm. 2</note> Nay, let vs breake their <hi>bands,</hi> and caſt their <hi>coardes</hi> from vs.</p>
               <p>Well, the <hi>primitue Church</hi> neuer knew ſuch Crowes, the Kyte of Rome
<pb facs="tcp:1606:12"/> bred them, they be hys broode, not ours, they lyue onelye vppon hys foode, and where ſhall wee haue to feede them?</p>
               <p>It is manyfeſt, that the Offici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als,<note place="margin">Melanc: in ſuo o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puſc: de vtra<expan>
                        <am>
                           <g ref="char:abque"/>
                        </am>
                        <ex>que</ex>
                     </expan> parte ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crame<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>. Ibidem.</note> and Commiſſaries as they call them, doo vſe an vngodlye libertie and power not to be ſuffered.</p>
               <p>And what helpeth it, to haue ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nye Counſayles, Aſſemblies, and Parlamentes, if Byſhops wyll ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer nothing to be reformed contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rye to their mynde.</p>
               <p>So long as this tyranny remay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neth<note place="margin">Idem.</note> how can the Churche bee hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led? Surely ſo many as allow the Popes ordinaunces, and mayn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tayne his doctrine, traditions, and inuented ſeruice, to honour God wyth, they infect and pollute them ſelues wyth Idolatrye, and blaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phemous opinions, they are gyltie alſo of all the bloude of the fayth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full, whych the Pope doth perſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute, they miniſhe alſo the glorye
<pb facs="tcp:1606:13"/> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the ſaluation of hys people, for as much as they confirme errours, and abominable wyckednes vnto all theyr poſteri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tye for euer.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <bibl>ROM. VIII.</bibl> If God bee wyth vs, who can be againſt vs?</q>
            </epigraph>
            <pb facs="tcp:1606:13"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
